<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Speakers on </title>
    <link>https://jdd-eeats.github.io/en/speakers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Speakers on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://jdd-eeats.github.io/en/speakers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About Us</title>
      <link>https://jdd-eeats.github.io/en/speakers/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jdd-eeats.github.io/en/speakers/about/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>François Paysant</title>
      <link>https://jdd-eeats.github.io/en/speakers/fran%C3%A7ois-paysant-000-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jdd-eeats.github.io/en/speakers/fran%C3%A7ois-paysant-000-04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;François PAYSANT is a doctor by training, specialized in forensic medicine. He is currently a senior lecturer at UGA, a hospital practitioner, and a researcher at the CERDAP2 Laboratory. After his medical training, he pursued studies in health law. He has successively participated in the work of an animal ethics committee, a research ethics committee, presided over the ethics and deontology commission at the Faculty of Medicine, and is currently a member of UGA&amp;rsquo;s ethics committee, a member of UGA&amp;rsquo;s valorization commission, and the UGA Scientific Integrity Officer. He has been an elected member of the National University Council (CNU) for his specialty since 2016, a member of the board of directors of the French Society of Forensic Medicine, and an expert at the Court of Appeal of Grenoble.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gauthier CHICOT</title>
      <link>https://jdd-eeats.github.io/en/speakers/gauthier-chicot-000-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jdd-eeats.github.io/en/speakers/gauthier-chicot-000-01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Gauthier Chicot, Ing., PhD, is the CEO and co-founder of DiamFab. After completing his engineering studies in Electronics at Polytech’ Grenoble, he earned his PhD in Nanoelectronics and Nanotechnology from the University of Grenoble in 2013. At the CEA and CNRS, his research primarily focused on ultra-wide band gap semiconductors, specifically the development of power electronics components using diamond. He particularly concentrated on optimizing the performance of these components in direct relation to epitaxial diamond layers during a post-doctoral research position at G2ELab. Leveraging this expertise, he began working in 2017 to commercialize the research outcomes from CNRS/Institut Néel, which led to the founding of the startup DIAMFAB in 2019, which he has led since its inception.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jean Christophe Crébier</title>
      <link>https://jdd-eeats.github.io/en/speakers/jean-christophe-cr%C3%A9bier-000-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jdd-eeats.github.io/en/speakers/jean-christophe-cr%C3%A9bier-000-02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jean-Christophe Crébier is a CNRS researcher at the Grenoble Electrical Engineering Laboratory (G2Elab). With over 20 years of research experience in various fields of power electronics (semiconductors, 3D packaging, integrated drivers, multicellular converters, etc.), his current work focuses on identifying the conditions for the sustainability of power electronics technology. He is also the CSR representative for his laboratory, and at the national level, he co-leads working groups on more sustainable electronics. More recently, he has become involved in coordinating the Reflection Group of the GDR labo1point5.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kevin Parisot</title>
      <link>https://jdd-eeats.github.io/en/speakers/kevin-parisot-000-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jdd-eeats.github.io/en/speakers/kevin-parisot-000-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Comedian, director, and writer with the collective La grosse Clique, which he co-leads, he is also a theater workshop instructor for Créarc and the Jean-Wiéner Conservatory in Échirolles. Kevin is bilingual in English and French and holds a PhD in cognitive science, with expertise in visual perception, attention, and eye movements. Today, he focuses on two main areas within the performing arts: his artistic creations (acting, directing, and writing) and the transmission of practices (theater and writing workshops, as well as scientific outreach).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kyllian Millard</title>
      <link>https://jdd-eeats.github.io/en/speakers/kyllian-millard-000-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jdd-eeats.github.io/en/speakers/kyllian-millard-000-14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kyllian Millard holds an engineering degree in Physics Engineering, obtained in 2020 from INSA Toulouse. He went on to pursue a PhD at CEA-Leti focused on developing a complex routing system in silicon nitride integrated photonics, aimed at creating a projector for augmented reality glasses. He defended his thesis in November 2023. Since 2024, he has been working at Steerlight as a photonic design engineer, developing a third-generation LiDAR system.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Location</title>
      <link>https://jdd-eeats.github.io/en/speakers/location/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jdd-eeats.github.io/en/speakers/location/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Martial Defoort</title>
      <link>https://jdd-eeats.github.io/en/speakers/martial-defoort-000-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jdd-eeats.github.io/en/speakers/martial-defoort-000-11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Martial Defoort completed his master&amp;rsquo;s degree at Joseph Fourier University, Grenoble (Condensed MaAer and Radiatioon Physics), aEer which he conducted a PhD on the nonlinear behavior of nano-resonators at low temperatures. Following this training in fundamental physics, he pursued a career in applied physics, focusing on micro/nano-sensors and their use in exotic regimes, which is currently at the core of his research as a CNRS Research Scienttist at the TIMA laboratory.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mathilde Billaud</title>
      <link>https://jdd-eeats.github.io/en/speakers/mathilde-billaud-000-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jdd-eeats.github.io/en/speakers/mathilde-billaud-000-06/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A chemical engineer by training (Engineering School of Chemistry in Montpellier, with a specialization in materials), she discovered microelectronics during her PhD at EEATS, carried out jointly at CEA-Leti and LTM (a CNRS laboratory). Her thesis, completed in 2017, focused on the integration of III-V semiconductor materials into MOSFET transistors. She then developed expertise in the environmental challenges of electronics at the Fraunhofer Institute (IZM) in Berlin, Germany, where she worked on fixed-term contracts for six years before returning to Grenoble. Since November 2023, she has been a researcher (on a fixed-term contract) in CEA-Leti’s eco-innovation program, specializing in packaging and 3D integration technologies. Her work particularly aims to advance circular economy approaches and the repairability of integrated circuits.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poster Instructions</title>
      <link>https://jdd-eeats.github.io/en/speakers/poster/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jdd-eeats.github.io/en/speakers/poster/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sergio Vinagrero</title>
      <link>https://jdd-eeats.github.io/en/speakers/sergio-vinagrero-000-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jdd-eeats.github.io/en/speakers/sergio-vinagrero-000-09/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sergio Vinagrero received his engineering degree from the University Carlos III in Madrid and received the PhD in Nanoelectronics in 2024 for his work on the modelling and analysis of Physical Unclonable Functions (PUFs). He is currently pursuing a postdoc in Ecole Centrale de Lyon and TIMA Laboratory on the development of security protocols leveraging photonic PUFs. His research interests are on Hardware Security, Test and Reliability analysis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sophie Bouccara</title>
      <link>https://jdd-eeats.github.io/en/speakers/sophie-bouccara-000-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jdd-eeats.github.io/en/speakers/sophie-bouccara-000-13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sophie has a doctorate in life sciences. After 2 post-doctorates and teaching experience, she joined Adoc Talent Management in a multi-skilled position focusing on PhD profiles. She is a researcher at the LID, a recruitment consultant and a trainer. She works in particular on the career paths of PhDs and is involved in European projects on research careers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sophie Panel</title>
      <link>https://jdd-eeats.github.io/en/speakers/sophie-panel-000-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jdd-eeats.github.io/en/speakers/sophie-panel-000-05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sophie PANEL is a senior lecturer in economics at Sciences Po Grenoble and a researcher at the Pacte Laboratory. After earning her PhD in 2015 from the University of Heidelberg, she worked at Sciences Po Bordeaux, the Research Institute for Strategic Studies at the École Militaire, and the Free University of Brussels. She is the scientific integrity officer at UGA.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sponsors &amp; Partners</title>
      <link>https://jdd-eeats.github.io/en/speakers/sponsors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jdd-eeats.github.io/en/speakers/sponsors/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thomas Dalgaty</title>
      <link>https://jdd-eeats.github.io/en/speakers/thomas-dalgaty-000-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jdd-eeats.github.io/en/speakers/thomas-dalgaty-000-07/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Undergrad studies at University of Glasgow and ETH Zurich. PhD between CEA-Leti and institute of neuroinformatics (Uni. Of Zurich). Researcher at CEA-List since 2020. Main publications in Nature, NeurIPS and CVPR on the topics of analogue, in-memory and in-sensor computing and computer architectures. CEA expert status since 2024.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
